你是要我解说 你是怎么输的?
So you want me to,explain how you just lost?
还是要盯着棋盘发呆整整...三分钟?
Or do you wanna stare at the,board your full... three minutes?
永不言弃?
Cling to hope?
快点 这可是快棋
Come on. It's called speed chess.
呐 呐
Na na na na
na na na na
嗨 嗨
hey hey hey
再见了
good-bye
下得不错
good game.
我说下得不错
I said good game.
嗨 嗨
Hey!Hey hey!
你在干吗 住手 孩子 住手!
What are you doing?,Stop that, son! Stop that!
过来 过来!
Back away from him. Back away!
打911 叫辆救护车!
Call 911.Get an ambulance!
让他们派两辆来!
Tell them to send two!
我的头快爆炸了 啊!
My head's gonna explode! Aah!
-=怪杰医生豪斯=-,第三季 第23集,"混球"; "The Jerk"
House M.D,Season 03 Episode 23
你的头还疼吗?
Your head still hurt?
你傻啊?
You a moron?
Nate.
Nate
我j紧攥着脑袋 他还问我疼不疼?
I'm clutching my head in,pain, and he asks if it hurts?
你是什么 医学院的学生啊?
What are you, some kind of med student?
你看起来还是乳臭未干
You look like you still,have theme birthday parties.
对不起
Sorry.
最近上课能集中精神吗?
Any problems concentrating,in school lately?
除了想着舔遍法语老师的乳房
Besides the dreams of running my tongue,along my french teacher's breasts?
还成 精神挺集中的
No,I'm doing quite great.
狂躁和疼痛可能是寄生虫引起的,他吃很多寿司吗?
The rage and pain could be caused by,a parasite. Does he eat a lot of sushi?
不 直到几个月以前 他都只吃素食
No. Uh,he was a vegetarian,until just a few months ago.
改变食谱后他的举止有变化吗?
Any changes in behavior,since the new diet?
没有
No.
他从十几岁开始就这样了
He's been this way since,he became a teenager.
不管我怎么叫怎么罚 他还是会说...
It doesn't matter how much I yell,or punish, he's still gonna say-
是啊 为可怜的Nate他妈流流眼泪吧
yeah,let's all shed a tear,for poor little nate's mother.
还有什么蠢问题吗?
Any more stupid questions?
nate.
Nate
我讨厌这小孩
I hate this kid.
我喜欢这小孩
I like this kid.
- 你还没见过他,- 知道你讨厌他就够了
- You haven't met him.,- I know you hate him.
还需要了解别的什么?,这孩子与众不同啊
What more do I need to,know? The kid's not a clich?
普通人输了才会打架
Anybody can get into,a fight after losing.
但揍你刚刚击败的人一顿...有创意
It takes real creativity to,beat up someone you just beat.
他不光脑袋疼
The pain's not limited to his head.
他这个学期打了17次架 四处伤痕累累
The rest is bumps and bruises accounted for,by the 17 fights he's been in this semester.
脑震荡?
Concussion?
核磁共振显示正常 没有额叶瘤
Mri was clean. No frontal lobe tumor.
毒性筛检也显示没有使用,可卡因或者安非他命的痕迹
And the tox screen showed no,trace of coke or amphetamines.
Nate打人野蛮粗暴 可能是...
Nate went medieval on,the other kid. Could be-
等等 我情绪激动
hold on. I'm having a moment.
这...
This...
这可能是Foreman最后一次,错误地认为是肾上腺肿瘤
this could be Foreman's last time,mistakenly suggesting adrenal gland tumor.
肾上腺瘤会导致肾上腺素分泌过量,引起他的头疼和狂躁
Which could create excess adrenaline.,Causes the head pain and rage.
但解释不了人格紊乱
But not the personality disorder.
没有什么人格紊乱
there is no personality disorder.
他处于青春期
He's a teenager.
处于青春期,能解释一些古怪无礼的言论
Being a teenager excuses the,odd inappropriate comment.
可这孩子说的没一句像人话
This kid say anything appropriate?
他得了丛集性头痛,说不定已经许多年了
He's having cluster headaches.,Probably been having them for years.
问题在于 是由什么导致的?
Question is, what's causing them?
如果只是丛集性头痛,他的眼睛四周应该肿胀才对
If it were just a cluster headache,,he'd have swelling around the eyes.
急诊用布洛芬给他止痛,止不了这种头痛
Er gave him ibuprofen for,the pain. Useless for this pain.
但可能消除了肿胀,最可能是血管上的问题
But it could have knocked down the,swelling. Best bet is a vascular problem.
正常治疗丛集性头痛是用类固醇,急诊也给他用了
Normal treatment for cluster headaches,is steroids, which the ER also gave him.
他还是疼 也就说明...
He's still in pain. Which means-
正常治疗之所以叫做"正常",是因为 有时不得不用"特殊"治疗
normal treatment is called normal treatment because,sometimes you have to use abnormal treatment.
给他用抗凝血剂 做轻度经颅磁刺激
Start him on blood thinners and give his,noggin transcranial magnetic stimulation.
看你敢不敢 碰那个毒舌才子
Don't you dare...,touch that acerbic wit.
你们谁去治这兔崽子 我就给谁50美元
50 bucks to whichever of you,steps up and treats this brat.
不是这孩子的错 他病了
Not the kid's fault, he's sick.
好吧 你来做
Fine. You do it.
没门 这兔崽子是你的
No way. He's your brat.
我去做 但我做完后要去工作面试
I'll do it. But I've got,a job interview after work.
后面出现什么情况 就由你们来处理了
Anything comes up later,,you guys handle it.
- 要一封同事推荐信吗?,- 多谢了
- Need a peer recommendation?,- Thanks.
Cameron写就够了
Cameron's should suffice.
这东西不会让我变成,流口水 尿裤子的植物人吧?
This isn't gonna turn me into some,like,,drooling vegetable that wets his pants,is it?
这很安全 电磁脉冲激活神经细胞,希望能消除头疼
It's safe. The magnetic pulses activate nerve,cells which will hopefully squelch the head pain.
其他地方疼有办法吗?
Is there anything you can,do about the other pain?
打架留下的?
From the fights?
是啊 我的脸 肩膀 肚子
Yeah,I mean,my face,,my shoulder. My stomach.
还有 我几乎弯不了手指
I mean,I can barely bend my fingers.
你已经服用止痛药了 我也没别的办法
You're already on pain,meds. Nothing more I can dO.
你能帮忙 叫你的兄弟不要整我
Sure you can,man. Tell your,homies to quit stomping on me.
我会放出消息说 你是个不错的家伙
I'll get the word out,that you're a great guy.
别人在你面前 是不是说话小心翼翼的?
So,do people watch what,they say around you?
因为我是黑人?
Because I'm black?
不 因为你是基佬
No,because you're gay.
丛集性头痛可能持续多年
cluster headaches can persist for years,
导致易怒甚至对他人的敌意
cause irritability or even,hostility towards others.
你是说疾病影响了他的性格?
You mean,the illness is,affecting his personality?
如果治疗见效的话 可能...
If these treatments work, it could-
改变他?
change him?
是的
Yeah.
谢天谢地
Oh,thank god.
哦 你一定觉得我不是个好妈妈
Oh. Oh,you must think I'm awful.
我儿子还躺在病床上...
Here my son's lying,in a hospital bed and-
- 我却...,- 我非常理解你的心情
I -I'm pretty sure I get it.
我认为我是个不合格的母亲
I thought I was a bad mother.
我憎恶我自己
And I hated myself.
因为我憎恶他
Because I hated him.
天气这么好 有何对我报?
what have you got for,me this fine morning?
抗血凝剂和经颅磁刺激没效果,不是丛集性头痛
Blood thinners and tms had no,effect. It's not cluster headaches.
你指责症状在骗人?
You accusing the symptoms of lying?
可能是血色病
Could be hemochromatosis.
解释不了人格紊乱
Wouldn't account for the,personality disorder.
那甲状腺机能减退呢?
What about hypothyroidism?
他的症状不是挑衅和嗜眠,而是越来越挑衅
He's not getting aggressive and lethargic,he's,getting aggressive and aggressiver.
会不会是皮样囊肿破裂?
What about ruptured dermoid cyst?
抱歉 刚刚头晕了 我本来想往右转
Sorry. Just got dizzy there.,I was expecting to turn right.
该轮到Foreman的见解遭否定了
It's Foreman's turn to be shot down.
和Cameron想的一样
The thing that Cameron said.
真是打破惯例思考问题的好方式啊
Way to think outside the box.
但脑室没有肿大
But no fat in the ventricles.
是丛集性头痛
It's cluster headaches.
正常治疗没有见效,特殊治疗也没有见效
normal treatment didn't work.,Abnormal treatment didn't work.
说得好 Foreman
Good point,Foreman.
治疗不一定见效 症状从不骗人
The treatments don't always,work. Symptoms never lie.
治疗丛集性头痛的合法手段,只剩下脑部手术了
the only approved treatment left for,cluster headaches is brain surgery.
手术也不能保证成功
And that's not even a guarantee.
别废话 Foreman!
Back off,Foreman!
如果合法治疗无效 那就用非法手段
If the approved treatment doesn't,work, we go with an unapproved treatment.
嗨!
Hey!
你想说什么吗?
Something on your mind?
你根本说不出来
Because you totally can't tell.
我昨天预约了纽约Mercy医院的面试
I had a job interview lined up,at new york mercy yesterday.
曼哈顿大人物的专属医院,真是妙计 你的兄弟们一定为你自豪
Hospital for manhattan's glitterati.,Big coup. Your homies must be kvelling.
没有去 说我打电话去取消了
Didn't happen,because,apparently I called to cancel.
我不记得我有打那个电话,你说我是不是得了神经学的病?
I don't remember making that call.,You think I have neurological issue?
- 是的,- 你为什么要摆布我?
- Yes.,- Why are you jerking me around?
- 不是我干的,- 是啊
- It wasn't me.,- Yeah.
那肯定是某个卑鄙压抑的,混蛋老板干的
It was one of the other petty,,socially repressed asses I work for.
说不定是艾什顿·库奇干的,(恶搞节目Punk'd的主持人)
Maybe it was ashton kutcher.
如果你想我留下 直接告诉我
If you want me to stay,tell,me you want me to stay.
- 有差吗?,- 没有 但成年人就该这么处理
Would it matter? No,but it'd,be the adult way to handle it.
反正没有用 何必多费力?
If the adult way doesn't,work,why bother with it?
我很有职业精神,提前两周通知 完成未结病例
I've been totally professional! Gave two,weeks notice,continued to work cases.
在私人时间去面试
Scheduled my interviews on my own time.
你没有权利毁了我的前途
You have no right to,screw with my future.
鉴别诊断的时候你会不停抱怨的 是吧?
You're gonna be all whiny during,the differential diagnoses,aren't you?
不是我干的
It wasn't me.
我只妨碍我认为值得妨碍的人
I only sabotage people I,consider worth it.
你这个恶毒狡猾的女人
You are one evil,cunning woman.
这句话可够刺激的
It's a massive turn-on.
你们可以晚点再八卦
You girls can gossip later.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
你给纽约Mercy医院打电话,让Foreman的工作面试胎死腹中
You called new york mercy to,have Foreman's job interview killed.
我说 "你们可以晚点再八卦",就是礼貌的叫你快出去
When I said,"you girls can gossip later,",I was throwing you out,but in a polite way.
我猜你已经不服用抗抑郁药了
Well,I take it you're,off your antidepressants.
啊 你在改变话题 只有我才能那么做
Ah,you're deflecting.,Only I'm allowed to do that.
Foreman真认为是我做的?
Does Foreman actually think I did that?
不 只是我这么想,但我清楚一件事 不是我干的
No,just me. But I know something he,doesn't. I didn't do it.
我为什么会那么做?
Why would I do it?
- 你想他离开吗?,- 不
- Do you want him to leave?,- No.
你打算采取什么行动吗?
Were you planning on doing something?
我在等董事会通过
I'm waiting for board approval.
但如果他找到新工作 就没办法干涉了,你得阻止他
But if he takes the job, there's,nothing to be done. You had to stop him.
不是我干的
Wasn't me.
你在干吗?
What are you doing?
寻找迹象 快速眨眼 嘴唇抽搐
Looking for a tell. Rapid,eye blink,twitch of the lips.
出门时 顺便吧Unger护士叫进来
Send in nurse unger when you,pass her on your way out.
差点忘了 要用神奇蘑菇给16岁的病人,治疗丛集性头痛 可以吧?
Almost forgot. I need to give a 16-year-old magic,mushrooms to treat a cluster hdache. Is that cool?
好啊 没问题
Yeah,no problem.
我是在说反话
I was being sarcastic.
法院笔录上可不会这么陈述
Wouldn't look that way in,the court transcript.
神奇蘑菇(一种毒品)含有裸盖菇碱,对丛集性头痛有效
Mushrooms have psilocybins that,work on cluster headaches.
不这么做 就只能切开他的脑袋探索了
It's either that,or,cutting into his brain
我想你考虑到他可能会经历心理紊乱?
I assume you've considered he could,have a psychogenic experience.
可能会遭受强烈的妄想症
Possibly suffer a fit of severe paranoia.
我现在意识到了
Well,I have now.
由院长来开处方,肯定比嗑药的疯医生来开要好
Yeah,it's definitely better that the dean of medicine prescribes,it instead of an unhinged doctor with a history of drug use.
如果病人决定穿上披风 从屋顶跳下翱翔,我也可以脱罪
Takes the stink off if the patient,decides to put on a cape and fly off the roof.
低剂量 不许超过10毫克 严谨监控
Low dose. No more than ten,milligrams. Tightly controlled setting.
还有必须先取得母亲的同意
And make sure the mother signs off on it.
省省心 Garth 别阻挡Foreman的前程,那可是大错特错 (Garth: 喜剧人物)
Party on,garth. And don't stand in,Foreman's way. It's just wrong.
最新研究发现毒蘑菇的化学成分会...
New research shows that a chemical,component in the mushrooms can be-
一大堆技医学上的行话,我什么时候才能吃到?
yeah,lots of technical medical,stuff. So when do I get 'em?
我上过大学 知道毒蘑菇的事
I went to college. I know about mushrooms.
朋友的朋友往自己脚上开了一枪
A friend of a friend shot,himself in the foot.
他们不会给我枪的 Enid!
They're not giving mea gun,enid!
快签同意书
Sign the consent form.
我们会看着他 但心脏停跳是有可能的
We'll be monitoring him, but,cardiac arrest is possible.
大人E
big E...
小孩N
small N...
如果毒蘑菇没有用呢?
and if the mushrooms don't work?
那么下一步就是脑部手术
The next step would bea,type of brain surgery.
我的天啊
Oh,god.
越来越痛了
Pain's gettin' worse.
快给我蘑菇!
Need 'sh rooms now!
*In-a-gadda-da-vida honey*,*在伊甸园 亲爱的*
In-a-gadda-da-vida,honey
*don't you know that I'm lovin' you*,*难道你不懂我爱你*
don't you know that I'm lovin' you
*in-a-gadda-da-vida baby...*,*在那伊甸园 亲爱的...*
in-a-gadda-da-vida,baby...
爽啊
oh,yeah.
Nate 还痛吗?
Nate,how's the pain?
*that I'll always be true...*,*我会一直真诚地...*
That I'll always be true...
嘿嘿! 是Skippy!
hey,hey!It's skippy!
灌木袋鼠!,(Skippy: 电视剧角色 后指澳洲白人)
The bush kangaroo!
你的脑袋 Nate 我们得知道还疼不疼
Your head,nate. We need,to know how the pain is.
我感受到的和疼痛完全相反
What I got here is the opposite of pain.
也就是说你得的是丛集性头痛,也就是说有希望...
That means you're suffering from cluster,headaches. Which means,hopefully-
伙计 你真性感
Man,you're hot.
- 她让我欲火焚身,- 忍忍吧
- She's making me horny.,- Deal with it.
嗨 嗨 嗨
Hey,hey,hey,hey.
你们不能让我飘飘欲仙又旮然而止
You can't get me stoned,then,not close the deal.
- 闭嘴,- 算了 他病了
- Shut up.,- Take it easy. He's not well.
如果拒绝你会后悔的
You'll regret saying no.
看吧
Check it out.
哦 看在上帝的份上
Oh,for god's sake.
- 等等,- 你到底干嘛?
- Hold it.,- What the hell are you doing?
他的睾丸偏小
He has undersized testes.
其它第二性征正常
His other secondary,sexual characteristics are normal.
想向我献殷勤,犯不着讨论其他男人的睾丸
If you wanna curry favor with me, avoid,discussions of other men's testicles.
谢谢
Thanks.
只需说"你对丛集性头痛的判断正确",就足够了
Focus on phrases like... "you were,right about the cluster headaches. "
但没说对病因
But wrong about what caused them.
主动脉血管疾病不会引起生殖官能不良
Vascular problem in a major artery,wouldn't cause hypogonadism.
好吧 那是什么导致脾气暴躁,头痛 人格紊乱还有生殖官能不良?
Okay,what causes rage,headaches,personality,disorder, and hypogonadism?
Foreman哪去了?
Where's Foreman?
他在生我的气
He's mad at me.
- 为什么?,- 没原因
- Why?,- No reason.
是啊 这说得过去
Yeah,that makes sense.
男性生殖器受下丘脑与垂体的控制
The male genitals are controlled by,the hypothalamus and pituitary gland.
我们再不提Foreman了
We're not talking about Foreman anymore.
这孩子在学校被人揍了
The kid's being pummeled at school.
头上挨几拳会损伤下丘脑
A couple blows to the head,could cause hypothalamic lesions.
能讨论下等Foreman走后,会有什么改变吗?
We ever gonna talk about what,happens when Foreman's gone?
如果这里像斯堪的纳维亚航空公司,是员工说了算 有可能会讨论
If this were an employee-owned,airline in scandinavia,yes.
不是外伤 否则他体温会不稳定,症状不会撒谎
It's not lesions. His temperature would be,all over the map. Symptoms don't lie.
他一周不到就走人了,你一份简历还没过目?
He's gone in less than a week,and you haven't even read a resume?
用不着 我们两个人足以应付了
Doesn't even need to. The,two of us can handle it.
颅咽管瘤符合症状
Craniopharyngioma fits the symptoms.
活检这臭小子的垂体
Biopsy the brat's pituitary.
让检验报告来证明,我对丛集性头痛判断正确
And let the record show I was,right about the cluster headaches.
不行
Forget it.
方法很简单 经鼻孔入路
It's a straight forward procedure.
从我脑袋里切除什么? 不行
and cut something out,of my brain? No way.
如果是瘤 你会丧命的
If it's a tumor,it could kill you.
那就多给我些蘑菇行吧? 我会没事的
Just give me more,'shrooms,okay? I'll be fine.
只要我同意就行了 对吧?
You only need my consent,right?
是的 最好是他配合...
Yeah,but it'll be a lot easier if he-
随你们采取什么措施吧
do whatever you have to do.
你别碰我 行吗?,你可以碰我 只要不是脑袋
You don't touch me,all right? You,can touch me. Just not my brain.
Nate 你得做这个测试,我再也忍受不了了
Nate,you gotta do this.,I can't take it anymore.
我的天 妈妈!,别那么歇斯底里了 行吗?
My god,mom! Save me the,melodramatic hand-wringing,okay?
放松点!去找个人做爱吧
Loosen up! Get yourself coited.
我要给他来针镇定剂
I'm gonna give hima sedative.
你看起来文质彬彬的 澳洲袋鼠医生
You're decent-looking, Dr. Skippy.
干嘛不跟她去嘿咻一番
Why don't you take her for a ride?
Nate...
你感觉痛吗?
Are you in pain?
Nate!
心跳正常 呼吸平稳
His heart rate's normal.,Respiration's even.
发生什么了?他怎么了?
What's happening? What's,the matter with him?
黄疸病 他的肝脏在衰竭
he's jaundiced. His,liver's shutting down.
开始给他用聚苯乙烯磺酸钠,(治疗肾病)
we started him on sodium,polystyrene sulfonate.
他的肝脏只有20%在起作用,还在迅速恶化
His liver's operating at about,20% and deteriorating fast.
也就是远在Foreman交出停车位前,他就会挂掉
Which means he'll be dead long before,Foreman turns in his parking pass.
那么 是什么导致人格紊乱 头痛
So,what causes personality,disorder, head pain,
等等和肝功能衰竭?
blah blah blah,and liver failure?
肝功能衰竭会导致生殖官能不良和头痛
Liver failure can cause,hypogonadism, head pain.
精神状态变化会引发人格紊乱和暴怒
Altered mental status leads to,the personality disorder and rage.
只需要找出肝功能衰竭的原因
All we need to do is figure out,what caused the liver failure.
没错 还得弄明白今天的肝功能衰竭,如何能导致昨天的症状
Yes-also,we need to figure out how symptoms,yesterday can be caused by liver failure today.
如果现在他的肝脏衰竭,那昨天也好不到哪去
If his liver's failing,now,it wasn't great yesterday.
如果肝脏运转不良,很可能会导致
If it wasn't operating at,capacity, it could have caused-
哇!
ooh-aah!Whoa!
别这样鬼鬼祟祟藏在背后
Don't sneak up on a person like that.
我在听
I'm listening.
倾听帮不上什么忙
Well,listening doesn't help me.
好 来探讨下肝脏和时间机器理论
Okay. Let's go with the,liver and a time machine theory.
Foreman 什么会导致肝脏问题?
Foreman,what causes liver problems?
威尔森氏症 (铜离子代谢异常)
Wilson's disease.
不是 他的血浆铜蓝蛋白水平正常
No. Ceruloplasmin's normal.
没有增大 也无可触及肿块 所以不是癌
No enlargement and no,palpable mass, so no cancer.
可能是胆管狭窄,原发性硬化性胆管炎
Could be a narrowing of the bile,ducts. Primary sclerosingcholangitis.
肝脏受损多因吸收进体内的东西,Foreman?
Most liver damage begins with what,we put in our bodies. Foreman?
愤怒的青少年...酒精
Angry teen... alcohol.
不对 酒精测试为阴性
No,blood tests were negative.
毒性筛检没发现毒品或醋氨酚中毒
no signs of drug use or acetaminophen,poisoning in his tox screen.
也许饮用水受到污染
Maybe the water was contaminated.
那他妈妈也会生病
his mother would also be sick.
Cuddy?
像是有人撑腰 去吧
Sounded like someone with back. Go.
没有你呆滞目光的指引,我们也能应付过去
We'll try and muddle through,without your blank stare to guide us.
如果不是他吃下的坏东西,会是好东西吗?
So if it's not the bad things he's,putting in, what about the good things?
他曾被当成素食者抚养
he was raised a vegetarian.
曾被 意味着他长大成人了
Was raised. Means he's all grown up.
或者说他再也不是素食者了
Or he's not a vegetarian anymore.
他几个月前开始吃红肉
He started eating red,meat a few months ago.
除非他一直买疯牛肉吃
Unless he's been buying cuts of mad cow,
否则身体代谢牛肉没问题
his body would have no,problem metabolizing it.
如果他得了鸟氨酸氨甲酰转移酶缺乏症,就会有问题
It would if he had an otc deficiency.
身体无法代谢氨 因此损坏了肝脏
Body can't metabolize,nitrogen, damages the liver.
做个汉堡包检测
Run a hamburger test.
完全文如其义 往他身体里塞满肉
It's exactly what it sounds,like. Stuff him full of meat,
等他的氨水平彪升
wait for his ammonia levels to spike.
我给你双倍薪水
I'll double your salary.
如果被Chase和Cameron发现,他们会造反的
Chase and Cameron would,mutiny if they found out.
Chase和Cameron不会马上领导,自己的诊断小组
Chase and Cameron wouldn't be heading,up their own diagnostic group.
你跟House平级 你单独行医
You'll work in parallel with,House. It'll be your practice.
不同下属 不同病例 完全独立
Separate staff,separate,cases. Complete autonomy.
我干这行才三年
I've only been doing,this for three years.
跟着House干了三年,没比这更好的训练了
Three years under House.,No better training.
那万一出现我解决不了的病例呢?
And when that case comes,along that I can't figure out?
你知道我不得不求助谁
You know who I'd have to go to.
你也可以任由病人死掉 完全取决于你
Or you can just let that patient,die. That's completely up to you.
不行
No.
为什么?
Why?
他太邪恶了
He's evil.
他没破坏你的面试
He didn't sabotage your interview.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
因为那是我干的
Because I did.
我没有
I didn't.
你信我了,就是说你不确定是House干的
You believed me-means you're,not sure House did it.
好吧 总有人做了这事
Well,somebody did it.
这儿的人
Somebody here did it.
我不能在这里干下去
I can't work here.
这不是医疗程序
This isn't a medical procedure.
这不过是小医生Doogie让我吃垃圾
This is just about,doogie making me eat garbage.
我们得弄明白你的肝脏如何代谢蛋白质
Need to see how your liver,processes the proteins.
那就给我来点肉排和烤牛肉
Then get me a steak,some roast beef.
我从家里给他带些吃的怎么样?
What if I brought,him something from home?
得吃这里准备的,好确保里面没有化学成分
It has to be prepared here,so we know there's no chemicals
或防腐剂影响测试结果
or preservatives that,could affect the test results.
我才不吃这食物 医院雇的移民厨子,每小时5美金工钱 带着发网
I'm not eating anything prepared by $5-an-hour,immigrant hospital cooks in hairnets.
闭嘴!
Shut up!
要么你开吃
Either you start eating,
要么就让我把你五花大绑,把这些玩意硬塞进你喉咙
or I'm gonna strap you to this bed,and shove these down your throat
一块接一块 明白吗?
one by one-got it?
你不能对我发脾气
You can't get mad at me.
我病了
I'm sick.
你应该同情我才对
You're supposed to feel bad for me.
- 护士 把整套约束带拿来,- 好的 医生
- Nurse,full set of body restraints.,- yes,doctor.
相信我
Trust me.
如果你自己吃就好受些
It'll be a lot less,messy if you do it yourself.
你破坏了Foreman的面试
You killed Foreman's job interview.
- 为什么我...,- 有人这么做了
- Why would I-,- somebody did.
不是我 也不是House 就是说,是某个爱护House的人
Wasn't me,and it wasn't House, which means it has to,be somebody who thought he was protecting House.
也就是某个真心喜欢House的人
Which means it hasto be somebody,who actually likes House.
就是说 不是你,就是那个爱反穿裤子的夜班清洁工
Which means it's either you or the weird,night janitor who wears his pants backwards.
我希望Foreman离开
I want Foreman to leave.
House必须意识到,有人对他勇敢地进行反抗
House has to realize he needs,someone who stands up to him.
Cameron爱他 Chase怕他,而我纵容他
Cameron's in love with him,chase,is afraid of him, and I enable him.
- House需要遏制,- 我会给他
- House needs limits.,- I give him-
你批准使用神奇蘑菇
you authorize magic mushrooms.
House是个六岁的孩子,以为没父母管束更好
House is a six-year-old who thinks,he's better off without parents.
让他吃冰激凌 番茄酱 痛几次肚子,对他有好处
A few tummy aches after dinners of ice,cream and ketchup might do him some good.
你撒谎
You're lying.
纵容者不会阴谋反对,纵容者会给予支持
An enabler doesn't conspire,against, an enabler enables.
什么?
What?
你有妄想症
You're paranoid.
你打的电话
You made that call.
而那个电话反而让Foreman决意离去
And because of that call, you bacally,guaranteed Foreman's out of here.
我认为带着他在船上干活乐趣无穷
I thought it would be fun to,work on my boat with him.
你光膀子是因为皮肤癌很酷
And you went shirtless because,skin cancer looks cool.
我知道我晒伤了 但我并不担心
Well,I realize I got burnt.,I'm not too worried about that.
是这些白斑让我不安
It's these white marks,you know?
躺下
Lie down.
我是说 那艘船上全是铅涂料
I mean,that boat has,all sorts of lead paint,
到处都是化学物品
and there's chemicals everywhere.
当爸爸在船上干活
when daddy works on his boat,
他是不是有个,装满长颈棕色酒瓶的小冰箱
does he have a cooler with lots,of brown bottles with long necks?
爸爸喜欢躺在船上 晒着大太阳呼呼睡?
And does daddy like to lie down on,his boat and go nap-nap in the sun?
哦 到底怎么回事?
Oh!What-what the hell?
给你这个来换...
I will give you this for the...
你口袋里的1美元4毛1分
$1.41 in your pocket.
等等 你怎么知道...
Wait,how could you know...
一个灵媒曾说我有特异功能
a psychic once told me that I'm psychic.
嗨 其中一个二毛五是加拿大硬币
Hey,one of these quarters is canadian.
把注射器还给我
Give me back my syringe.
汉堡包压力测试显示他的氨含量没变化
Hamburger stress test showed no,change in his ammonia levels.
肝脏正常地将氨转化成尿素
Liver's properly converting the,ammonia into urea.
他没有鸟氨酸氨甲酰转移酶缺乏症
He doesn't have otc deficiency.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
对不起 我不该把自己的问题,发泄到病人身上
Sorry. I shouldn't have been taking,my problems out on the patient.
或者发泄到我身上 接受你的道歉
Or on me. Apology accepted.
- 让他挨饿,- 我们要找什么?
- Starve him.,- What are we looking for?
糖尿病脂肪变性会损伤他的肝脏
Diabetic steatosis would,screw up his liver.
让他饿一晚上 看是否出现血糖问题
Starve him overnight and,see if his blood sugar pops.
我们扰乱他的血糖指数,会让他再次暴怒
We mess with his blood sugar,we,could set off another rage.
没问题 你能摆平他
Not a problem. You can take him.
我要吃东西!
I want something to eat!
亲爱的 请别这样
- Honey,please don'T.
我不过想弄尿液样本 他就发狂了
I was just trying to get a,urine sample, and he went crazy.
我要吃东西!
I need to eat!
你别想再往我身体里扎针
You're not sticking anything else in me.
不过还有几个小时
It's just a few more hours.
你会伤着自己的
You're gonna hurt yourself.
我要伤害你!
I'm gonna hurt you!
我们一拿到尿液样本 就随便你了
As soon as we get a urine,sample, we can leave you alone.
你想要样本 给你该死的样本!
You want your sample?,Here's your damn sample!
Nate 别这样
Nate,don'T.
哦 天哪
Oh,my god.
Nate 你现在得躺回床上去
Nate,you need to get,back into bed. Right now.
生化组合试验和尿检表明,血尿是由肾衰竭引起的
chem panel and urinalysis confirms the,bloody urine was caused by kidney failure.
他在做透析治疗 他的余生都得如此
He's on dialysis. He's gonna,need it for the rest of his life.
此刻他的生命正在缩短
Which is shortening as we speak.
我们就像看着中文菜单,太多栏目太多症状了
We are looking at a chinese menu, and,we've got symptoms from too many columns.
会向我们多收费
They're going to overcharge us.
多器官衰竭可能意味着原发艾滋病毒感染
Multiple organ failure could,mean primary hiv infection.
也意味着得有人愿意和他上床
That would meansomeone,agreed to sleep with him.
何况血清检查是阴性的
Plus his serologyis negative.
他的尿酸略微升高
His uric acid's slightly elevated.
这国家10%的男性都有升高的-
10% of males in this,country have elevated-
所以我们只注意异常的反常态?
so we're only gonna pay attention,to abnormal abnormalities?
他塞饱了肉 肾脏不堪重荷,他的尿酸当然会-
We've been stuffing him with meat and his,kidneys are shot. Of course his uric acid-
可能是肝硬化或MCADD,(中链乙酰辅酶A脱氢酶缺乏症)
could be hepatic fibrosisor mcadd.
臭小子有基因疾病
The brat's got a genetic disorder.
做个基因测序 看有哪些能治疗的
Get the sequencing primers. See if,it's one of the ones we can treat.
我可以抽血 然后就要走了
I can draw some blood,but,then I gotta run.
工作面试?
Job interview?
如果是 你打算阻止我?
You gonna stop me if it is?
你做护士的工作 他们做医生的
You do the nurse stuff,they'll,do the doctor stuff.
这是为结婚登记做的血液测试?
This a blood test for a marriage license?
计划绑架我到马萨诸塞州或加拿大...
Plan on kidnapping me to,massachusetts or canad...
你给他打了什么?
what did you give him?
你们在治疗什么病吗?
Are you treating him for something?
镇静剂
Sedative.
他需要用镇静剂?
Did he need a sedative?
我需要 就是为了让他闭嘴,让我安静的抽血
I did. Just shutting him up so I,can draw some of his bloodin peace.
你来的时候就带着,你根本没给他机会
You walked in with that. You,didn't even give him a chance.
人都是本性难改的
People are what they are.
他在生病
He's sick.
粗鲁不是他的错
The rudeness isn't his fault.
如果他得的是肺结核 也不是他的错
If he had tuberculosis, it,wouldn't be his fault either.
但我也不会让他朝我咳嗽
But I still wouldn't let him cough on me.
- 嗨,- 嘿
- Hi.,- Hey.
你要去哪?
where are you going?
实验室 检查病人的血液有没有遗传-
The lab. We're testing our,patient's blood for hereditary-
Cuddy认为我破坏Foreman的面试
Cuddy thinks I,sabotaged Foreman's interview.
她要解雇我
She's gonna fire me.
我不信
I don't believe it.
她说这种行径太不守职业道德-
She said it was unprofessional and-
不 我是说我不信你的话
no,I mean I literally don't believe it.
Cuddy不会因为那种事情解雇你的
Cuddy wouldn't fire,youfor something like that.
意味着不是她骗你
Which means either she lied to you,
就是你骗我
or you're lying to me.
要是三年前你会相信我的
You so would have fallen,for that three years ago.
你就是想看看我的反应,想看到我为你难过
You were looking for a reaction. You,were looking for me to feel bad for you.
想要救你 可是我怎么能救得了你?
To save your skin. But,how am I gonna save you?
除非...
Unless...
你觉得我才是那个人
you think I'm the one who really did it.
Cuddy的逻辑是Foreman对House很有价值
Cuddy's logic was Foreman's,valuable to House.
我在意House 所以 我会做一切去挽留他
I care about House. Ergo,I,would do anything to save him.
而你的逻辑是...,我和你一样在意House 所以...
And your logic was... I care about,House as much as you do, ergo...
那不是我
it wasn't me.
我不在意House
I don't care about House.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
没人相信
No one does.
House对我而言 只是老板
House is nothing more than my boss.
Foreman对我而言 只是同事
Foreman's nothing more than a colleague.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
人人撒谎 但我不会
Everyone does. But it wasn't me.
没有肝硬化的标记
No markers for hepatic fibrosis.
也没有MCADD的
And nothing for mcadd.
Foreman在纽约的面试被搞鬼了
Foreman's interview in,new york got screwed up.
我听说了
I heard.
Foreman以为是House干的,House觉得是Cuddy
Foreman thought it was House,,House thought it was Cuddy.
Cuddy认为是Wilson,Wilson觉得是我
Cuddy thought it was,Wilson,Wilson thought it was me.
而你觉得是我?
And you think it was me?
你觉得我破坏Foreman面试?
You think I sabotaged Foreman?
- 我甚至不希望他在这儿,- 我知道
- I don't even want him here.,- I know.
那我为什么要-
Then why would I do-
我以为你给Foreman捣乱,就是想毁了Foreman
I think you sabotaged Foreman,just to sabotage Foreman.
别人有嫌疑 是因为别人想帮House,除了我
So everyone's a suspect because,everyone wants to help House. Except for me.
我有嫌疑 是因为我是个卑鄙,报复心重的混蛋?
I'm a suspect because I'm,a petty, vindictive jerk?
你真的觉得我会做那样的事?
You actually think I would,do something like that?
- 肯定是某人,- 不是我
- It was someone.,- It wasn't me.
不是von gierke病,(遗传性肝糖贮积病)
Negative for von gierke disease.
今天是星期二
And it's tuesday.
我知道
I know.
我喜欢你
I like you.
我知道
I know.
下周二见
See you next tuesday.
有发现
Found something.
他有部分HPRT酶缺乏症,(次黄嘌呤-鸟嘌呤磷酸核糖转移酶)
He's got a partial hprt,enzyme deficiency.
意味着可能是kelley-seegmiller综合症
Means he could,havekelley-seegmiller syndrome.
但那是部分缺乏,所以也可能不是kelley-seegmiller
But it's a partial deficiency. So,it may not be kelley-seegmiller.
对 共有两个选项,是或者不是
Yes. Those are the two,options. It is or it isn'T.
Kelley-seegmiller解释了攻击性人格
Kelley-seegmiller explains the,aggressive personality.
如果他有kelley-seegmiller,就不止会好斗 还会自残
If he d kelley-seegmiller, he wouldn't,just be aggressive, he'd be self-mutilating.
咬自己的嘴唇 重击自己的头
Chewing his lips,banging his head.
可爱的病,退行性 致命 无法治愈
Lovely disease.,Degenerative,fatal,incurable.
我好奇,这是不是Cameron持否定意见的原因
I wonder if that's,why Cameron's on the "not" side.
是这原因 还有症状不会骗人
That and the fact that,symptoms don't lie.
kelley-seegmiller携带者在压力大时自残
kelley-seegmiller carriers,self-mutilate when they're stressed.
他在加护病房里肝脏衰竭 肾脏不工作
He's in the icu with a,failing liver and no kidneys.
没错 他的生活真甜蜜
Yeah,his life is sweet.
他吃素 所以身体里的嘌呤有限
His vegetarian diet could have,limited the purines in his system,
减缓了疾病进程
slowing the disease's progress.
- 那么加速它,- 为什么?
- So let's speed it up.,- Why?
这样你们两个小孩就不会打架了
So you two kids will stop fighting.
并且 我不想等呼吸系统衰竭
Also,I don't feel like waiting,for respiratory failure.
Chase 想个办法让妈妈走开一会
Chase,find some way for the,mother to get lost for a while.
我去给这个小孩加压,直到他咬掉一个手指
I'm going to stress this,kid until he bites off a finger.
我被转移到老人病区吗 你是谁?
They move me to geriatrics? Who are you?
拐杖怪医
Dr. Mccaney.
会在这棋盘上杀得你屁滚尿流的人
The man who's gonna kick your,ass all over this chessboard.
- 我太虚弱了不能-,- 咬自己一口
- Yeah,well,I'm too weak,to- - bite yourself,yeah.
你需要一些液体能量
You need some liquid energy.
你要是不反对 我要给你打一剂肾上腺素
Now,if you consent,I'm gonna,give you this shot of adrenaline.
我不想下棋
I don't wanna play.
除了可能指向垂体问题和遗传疾病
Aside from being indicative of pituitary,issues and certain kinds of genetic disorders,
小睾丸也可能意味着...
small testicles also indicate...
你是个胆小鬼
that you'r a big chicken.
别让我弄音效
Please don't make me do the sound effect.
你就是要激我下棋
You're not gonna goad me into playing.
不觉得有必要刺激你
Didn't think I'd have to.
你抓住每个机会羞辱别人
Thought you'd just jump at the,chance of humiliating someone.
老瘸子优先
Age before cripple.
我要白棋
I'm white.
这 就 开始了!
It... is... on!
伯德开局 被动走法
Bird's opening. Passive approach.
懦夫的标志
Sign of a coward.
西西里防御 笨蛋的标志
Sicilian defense. Sign of an idiot.
傲慢需要赢得
Arrogance has to be earned.
告诉我你做了什么赢得傲慢
Tell me what you've done to earn yours.
我能走路
I can walk.
我的阴茎不出血
I don't bleed out of my penis.
将军
Check.
要知道 被折磨的天才和
You know,it's a real thin,line between tortured genius
无法赢得女孩的笨拙小孩,差别很细微
and awkward kid who can't,get girls because he's creepy.
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
让你不堪重压
To stress you out.
将军
Check.
没错 但为什么?
Yeah,but why?
本想告诉你,但估计不知道原因 你会更有压力
I'd tell you,but I figure it's more,stressful if you don't know why.
不过 我没觉得很有压力
Yeah,well... I'm not,feeling too stressed.
你知道没人喜欢你 对吧?
You know that no one likes you,right?
没错 难道有人喜欢你?
Yeah,well,anybody like you?
你快完蛋了
You're dying.
将军
Check.
该你走
Your move.
介不介意放弃你的国王?
Care to lay down your king?
你赢不了
You can't win.
你可以牵住我的皇后
You can pin my queen.
我的骑士到e7 你的国王走h8.
My knight to e7. Your king to h8.
牺牲车吃掉卒
Sacrifice rook takes pawn.
象受困 皇后到h5 将死
Bishop blocks. Queen to h5. Checkmate.
为了挽救你残存的尊严
Save what's left of your dignity.
放弃你的国王
Lay down your king.
废物
Crap.
他在惊厥
he's having a seizure.
- 静脉注射四毫克劳拉西泮,- 马上
- Four milligrams iv lorazepam.,- Right away.
我恨这个孩子
I hate this kid.
我喜欢这个孩子
I like this kid.
你得到那个工作了吗?
Did you get the job?
他们会通知我的
They're gonna let me know.
Kelley-seegmiller不会引起惊厥
Kelley-seegmiller didn't,cause this seizure.
那么就多一种症状 少一种诊断
So we've got one more,symptom, one less diagnosis.
他们应该要求提供推荐人吧?,你留下我的名字了吗？
I assume they're gonna call for,references? Did you give 'em my name?
没有
No.
淀粉样变性病能导致惊厥,而蛋白质堆积导致了器官衰竭
Amyloidosis can cause seizures, and the,protein buildup could cause organ failure.
但不会影响他的性格
Wouldn't alter his personality.
你填的推荐人是谁?
Whose name did you give?
我上一个老板
My last boss.
那可不太好看啊
Ouch. That can't look good.
我恨这孩子
I hate this kid.
也许我们面对的不是单一病症?,而是多重状况一起导致的?
What if we're not dealing with one,condition? What if it's multiple conditions?
不会的 一定是单一病症,总是单一的
Uh-uh,it's gotta be,one. It's always one.
没什么可以同时解释这一大票症状
Nothing explains this,constellation of symptoms.
一定漏掉了什么,也许这孩子在用药方面说了谎
We've gotta be missing something.,Maybe the kid lied about some medication.
也许他在隐藏什么
Maybe he's hiding something.
- 他有什么好隐藏的?,- 我怎么知道 也许他是个小混账?
- Why would he be hiding something?,- I don't know,because he's evil?
如果他真的是呢?
What if he is?
如果是症状在撒谎?,(人格紊乱不是症状)
What if the symptoms lied?
那么
There.
就只是简单一个病例,得了淀粉样变性的小混账
Now all we're looking at is a,simple,evil jerk with amyloidosis.
你不客观
You're not being objective.
是你提出淀粉样变性病的阿
Amyloidosis was your idea.
你刚才说得对,解释不了全部症状
You were right,it,doesn't fit the symptoms.
能解释了
Yeah,it does.
看着
Look.
你把性格因素去掉,因为你想恨这个孩子
You crossed it off because,you wanna hate the kid.
如果他是病症受害者 你就没法恨他
And you can't hate him if he's a victim-
你是希望他是受害者,因为你想相信人性本善
you want him to be a victim because,you wanna believe that people are good.
如果不好 一定是哪里得了病
And if they're not, it's,gotta be a chemical problem.
但有例外 有人不是好东西 也没病
Except they're not,and it's not.
给他灌免疫抑制剂
Flush him with immunosuppressants,
做个活检确认一下,再给他找个骨髓捐赠者
get a biopsy to confirm,,and find him a marrow donor.
他会怎么样呢?
what will happen to him?
有种叫淀粉样蛋白的物质,在他的器官中堆积
substances called amyloid proteins,build up in the body's organs,
使它们停止运作
shutting them down.
这种疾病很少见 是致命的
It's a fairly rare disease.,And I'm afraid it can be fatal.
那你准备怎么取它们出来?
So do you operateor,something to take them out?
他需要骨髓移植
He needs a bone marrow transplant.
Cameron医生正在骨髓库里寻找配对的
Dr. Cameron is searching the donor bank.
我们也会测试一下你的是否可用
We should test you as well.
一开始你们告诉我他有病的时候
when you first told me he was sick...
我还觉得高兴
I was... happy.
松了口气
Relieved.
可现在
Now...
Nate 我要从你的踝关节取一点神经
nate,I'm gonna takea small,piece of nerve from your ankle.
感到痛就告诉我
Let me know if you feel any pain.
我要烧起来了
I'm burning up.
你就不能像上次一样把我弄昏吗?
Couldn't you just knock me,out like you did last time?
我也想 但你的身体里不能有药物
Wish I could. But your,body has to be clear
要准备做骨髓移植
so it's ready for a marrow transplant.
X医生
hey,dr. X...
我知道 你想破脑袋来救我的命
I know you've busted,ass trying to save me.
这没什么
It's all right.
我没说要谢谢你
I wasn't gonna thank you.
只是想告诉你 你干得超烂
I was gonna tell youyou,really suck at this.
我们已经在全力以赴
We're doing our best.
我就是这个意思
That's sort of my point.
你全力以赴了还是很烂
Your best really sucks.
神经活检没有什么结果
Nerve biopsy was clean.
没证据表明是淀粉样变性病
No evidence of amyloidosis.
是你想出来的 别这么快放弃阿
It was your idea. Don't,give up on it so fast.
他发着烧 如果是两种症状,其中一种必然是炎症
He's running a fever. If it's two conditions,,one of them's gotta be an infection.
应该开始用抗生素,看看什么有反应 什么没有
We should start him on antibiotics,,see what clears up,what doesn't.
他呼吸困难吗?
Is he having trouble breathing?
嗯 胸腔里有炎症导致的粘液
Yeah,he has mucus in his,chest from an infection.
也可能是淀粉状蛋白沉积
Could also be an amyloid buildup.
继续用免疫抑制剂,找其他地方做活检 窦管
Keep him on immunosuppressants and,biopsy somewhere else, his sinuses.
看 现在有两个选择
Look,you got two choices.
徒劳地争辩一番 按我说的做,或直接按我说的做
Engage me in a futile argument then do,what I asked, or just do what I asked.
你还没准备好
You're not ready.
还有第三个选择,不按我说的做
There was a third choice.,Don't do what I asked.
你本可以违抗我,继续给那孩子用抗生素的 可你没有
You could have defied me,stuck the,kid on antibiotics. But you didn'T.
因为你仍然信任我的判断,比自己的还要信任
Because you still trust my,judgment more than your own.
是你破坏Foreman的面试的 对不对?
You sabotaged Foreman's,job interview, didn't you?
Foreman来闹过一次了,不是我
Foreman's already been,over this. It wasn't me.
每个人都在疑神疑鬼
Everybody's chasing ghosts over this.
说明要么没有人在搞鬼,要么有人希望所有人都疑神疑鬼
Which means either nobody did it, or,somebody wants everybody chasing ghosts.
这听起来像谁?
Now,who does that sound like?
为什么我要这么做?
And why would I do that?
因为只要Foreman认定是你做的
Because as long as,Foreman thought you were guilty,
他在这里就基本是废物了
he was gonna be useless around here.
这提醒我为什么要雇你了
You know,sometimes I,forget why I hired you.
你破坏了他一个大好机会,自己什么也没得到
You cost him a good,opportunity and gained nothing.
我破坏了他一个垃圾机会
I cost him a crappy opportunity.
在纽约Mercy医院只能治疖子和脓疱,养养老
New york mercy's where you go to,treat boils and cysts and build a 401k.
如果你想让他留下 告诉他
If you want him to stay,tell him.
我不要 这样做没有意义
I don't.And there'd be no point.
你必须
You do.
意义在于让他觉得自己是被需要的
And the point would be to make,him feel like he's wanted.
他不需要这个
He doesn't need that.
那么让他觉得你没那么邪恶
All right,then. It'd make him,feel like maybe you weren't evil.
他需要这个
He needs that.
跟Foreman谈谈
Talk to Foreman.
我们去掉了一个症状
We dumped one symptom.
但忘记了加上一个
But forgot to add one.
复仇时间到了 Nate
Revenge time,nate.
- 你是...,- 是的 我就是
- Are you...,- yes! I am.
要黑要白?
Black or white?
一边跛着去
Just limp away.
他不想下 就让他静静吧
He doesn't wanna play. Leave him alone.
选一方 要不就停药
Pick one,or this comes out.
事先声明 这药物很关键
And for all you know,this,is really important.
住手
Ow!Stop it!
很痛 对吧
That hurts,right?
好奇怪 我竟然感觉相当好
Which is odd, because,I'm really enjoying this.
你这么拿棋子 是因为不能弯曲拇指
You hold the pieces that way,because you can't bend your thumb.
因为你的骨头畸形了
Because your bones have,formed abnormally.
是有东西挤压骨头造成变形的
Thanks to all the crap that's been,pushing its way in between them.
事实上 这药没什么用
Actually,this stuff isn't,important at all.
医生说得让他用免疫抑制剂
Your doctors said he,needs immunosuppressants.
他们是白痴 不是淀粉样变性疾病
They're idiots. It's not amyloidosis.
是铁 他得的是血色沉着病
It's iron. He's got hemochromatosis.
身体吸收食物中的铁,但不能处理也不能排出
The body absorbs iron from food, but,can't process it. Can't get rid of it.
游手好闲的铁成了魔鬼游乐场
And idle iron is the devil's playground.
在骨头和器官中沉积
It builds up in the organs and joints,
一点点破坏它们
whacking them in the process.
造成了所有的症状
Caused all of the symptoms.
包括那些不是症状的症状
Including something that,wasn't a symptom.
身体上的疼痛 不是打架造成的
Those body aches,they,were not from the fighting.
那性格问题呢?
His personality issues?
抱歉
Sorry.
这点上铁是无辜的
The iron's innocent on that count.
你的小孩就是个混球,对 可能是你教育无方
Your kid's a jerk. And,yeah,it's probably your fault.
可是你若听妈妈的话 不吃肉
Although,if you'd stayed off,the meat like your mom said,
就会少摄入一半的铁,比现在多一倍的生气
you'd have half as much iron,,and be twice less almost dead.
护士
Oh,nurse!
病人因故出血
This patient is bleeding for some reason.
他会好起来吗?
Is he going to be okay?
他需要透析
He'll need dialysis.
需要几个月就把血抽干一次,持续一辈子
And he'll have to get his blood drained,every few months for the rest of his life.
我虽深表同情,但你会活漫长而痛苦的一生
But my condolences. It's going,to be a long and annoying life.
我不该吃你的象
And I wouldn't have taken your bishop.
应该把皇后走到d6 去除威胁
I'd have moved my queen,to d6,defusing the threat.
再走车到e8 攻击王前兵
Then rook to e8,attacking,the king's pawn.
赢不了兑换 但最终比赛我能胜
I'd have lost the,exchange,but won the game.
我知道
I know.
我是虚张声势的
I was bluffing.
而你也就
And that's why...
这么输了
You lost.
小混球
Little jerk.
你只是看热闹 还是想说些什么?
You just here to watch,or,you got something to say?
还在做淀粉样变性病的活检?
Still running the new,biopsy for amyloidosis?
是 还是没有
Yeah,but still nothing.
再做一遍 重新检查结果
Run the test again.,Recheck your results.
看样子有人要熬通宵了
Looks like you're in for an all-nighter.